Finding Aid for Woodrow W. and Ann Woody papers, 1931-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Woodrow W. and Ann Woody papers 1931-1998
Woody, Woodrow W.
2010069 Aa 2; Ac
Owner of Woody Pontiac Sales, Inc. in Hamtramck, MI and lifelong Republican and proponent of peace in the Middle East; correspondence, newspaper clippings, and photographs.
0.6 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated in February 2010 by Howard George (donor no. 10320 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Woodrow Woody was born Woodrow William Shikany in Bejdarfel, Lebanon on November 15, 1907. His family immigrated to the United States in 1912, settling in Minneapolis, Minnesota. While living in Minneapolis, Woody went to school, sold newspapers, and organized the St. Maron Athletic Club.
By 1929, the Shikany family had moved from Minneapolis to Detroit. During this time, Woody began his first job in the automobile industry working for the Hudson Motor Car Company installing axles. After a few years of assembling automobiles, Woody decided he would rather be responsible for selling automobiles. Woody got his opportunity in 1936 when the Mack-Gratiot Chevrolet Company hired him for a sales position. After less than two years of selling Chevrolets for Mack-Gratiot Chevrolet, Woody left the company to go into business for himself. He purchased a used car lot on Vernor and Mt. Eliot in Detroit and opened Liberty Motor Sales.
Soon after, in 1939, Woody applied for a Pontiac franchise in Hamtramck. Woody Pontiac Sales, Inc. was established on January 2, 1940. The dealership remained open for six decades until Woody closed the store 2000. During his many years as the senior Pontiac Dealer in Michigan, he also served as president of the Hamtramck Auto Dealers Association and the Detroit Metropolitan Pontiac Dealers Association. In 1994, Woody received the Automotive Hall of Fame's Distinguished Service Citation Award.
Along with the opening of Woody Pontiac Sales in the 1940s, Woody also served in the United States Army during World War II. After being honorably discharged in 1945 at the conclusion of the war, Woody married Ann Martes, a Polish-American from Hamtramck.
Besides his many accomplishments and responsibilities as an auto dealer, Woody was also the president of the Hamtramck Rotary, president of the World Lebanese Cultural Union, owner of Hillcrest Country Club in Mount Clemens, and the recipient of the St. Ursula Award for Humanitarianism. Additionally, Woody was a lifelong Republican and tireless proponent of peace in the Middle East.
Woodrow Wood died on April 3, 2002 at the Beaumont Hospital in Troy, Michigan at the age of 94.
The Woodrow and Ann Woody papers are organized into two series: Correspondence and other papers and Photographs. The collection consists primarily of correspondence with public figures; newspaper clippings, photographs, and other materials from scrapbooks relating to the Hillcrest Wolverine Open golf tournament; photographs of Woody and his wife Ann with various public figures and attending different social occasions.
Subjects:
Arab Americans--Michigan.; Automobile dealers--Michigan.; Golf--Tournaments--Michigan.; Hamtramck (Mich.); Hillcrest Wolverine Open (Golf tournament); Woody, Ann.; Woody, Woodrow W.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Automobile dealerships--Michigan.; Golf--Michigan.; Golfers--Michigan.; Hamtramck (Mich.); Hillcrest Golf and Country Club (Macomb County, Mich.); Hillcrest Wolverine Open (Golf tournament); John Paul II, Pope, 1920-2005.; Woody, Ann.; Woody Pontiac Sales (Hamtramck, Mich.); Woody, Woodrow W.
Contributors:
Woody, Ann.
Genre Terms:
CD-ROMs.; Photographs.
- Correspondence and other papers
  Correspondence and other papers series documents Woodrow Woody's life, politics, and association with Hillcrest Country Club in Mount Clemens, Michigan. The series consists of correspondence between Woody and various political figures primarily from the Republican Party, as well as newspaper clippings about Woody and his Pontiac dealership in Hamtramck. Additionally, the series contains two scrapbooks documenting the Hillcrest Wolverine Open during the years 1960 to 1964. The photographs, newspaper clippings, and other materials have been removed from the scrapbook and re-housed in folders.
  - Correspondence (arranged alphabetically), 2 folders
    - A-C
      - Abraham, Spencer 1998 (Box 1)
      - Atwater, Lee 1989 (Box 1)
      - Bonior, David 1993-1994 (Box 1)
      - Bouhabib, Abdallah 1988 (Box 1)
      - Bush, George H. W. 1989-1992 (Box 1)
      - Cohan, Leon S. (Box 1)
      - Conyers, John 1987 (Box 1)
      - Cynar, Walter P. 1989 (Box 1)
    - D-W
      - Engler, John 1995-1996 (Box 1)
      - Fisher, Max M. 1998 (Box 1)
      - Kattouf, Theodore H. 1990 (Box 1)
      - Kojelis, Linas 1988 (Box 1)
      - Lahoud, Nassib 1991 (Box 1)
      - Levin, Carl 1989 (Box 1)
      - Nixon, Richard 1971, 1990 (Box 1)
      - Nunn, Sam 1989 (Box 1)
      - O'Connor, John Cardinal (Box 1)
      - Pell, Claiborne 1989 (Box 1)
      - Quayle, Dan 1989 (Box 1)
      - Reagan, Ronald 1982-1983 (Box 1)
      - Riegle, Donald W. 1989 (Box 1)
      - Romney, George 1989 (Box 1)
      - Sfeir, Nasrallah-Pierre 1991 (Box 1)
      - Siv, Sichan 1990 (Box 1)
      - Solomon, Anthony J. 1989 (Box 1)
      - Super, Katherine L. 1992 (Box 1)
      - Vander Jagt, Guy 1989 (Box 1)
      - Wilcox, Philip C. 1987 (Box 1)
  - Address of Woodrow W. Woody to the American Arab Council, Hall of Nations International Institute 1967 (Box 1)
  - Hillcrest Wolverine Open Scrapbooks
    (includes photographs)
    - Volume 1 1960-1964, 4 folders (Box 1)
      (includes a photograph of Jack Hoffman with others and a news article on Joyce Ziske and Betsy Rawls in an oversize folder)
    - Volume 2 1963, 11 folders (Box 1)
      (includes a news article on the Hillcrest Bridge collapse in an oversize folder)
  - Macomb County Distinguished Citizen Award Program 1979 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 1)
- Photographs
  Photographs series contains images of Woodrow and Ann Woody with friends, politicians, or other prominent persons, including Presidents Richard Nixon, George H.W. Bush, Michigan Governors George Romney, William Milliken, James Blanchard, and John Engler, Pope John Paul II, as well as automobile executives, Michigan Congressmen, and Detroit Mayor Coleman Young. The series also contains photographs of the former Hillcrest Country Club in Mount Clemens and of the Woody Pontiac dealership in Hamtramck. There are also signed portraits of various public figures.
  - Ann Woody 1960s-1970s (Box 1)
  - Woodrow W. Woody 1931-1980s (Box 1)
  - Woodrow and Ann Woody 1946-1990s (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Woody with friends and family 1942-1994 (Box 1)
  - Woody with politicians and prominent figures 1950s-1990s, 3 folders (Box 1)
    (include Richard Nixon and other political figures, Pope John Paul and other religious leaders, automobile company executives, sports personalities)
  - Woodrow Woody's 82-birthday celebration 1989 (Box 1)
  - Hillcrest Country Club 1960s-1970s (Box 1)
    (includes oversize photograph)
  - Woody Pontiac Sales Store 1950s-1990s (Box 1)
    (also includes CD-ROM of images)
  - Signed Portraits of public figures 1960s-1980 (Box 1)